Finding Aid for the Hilda Kuper Papers LSC.1343
UCLA Library Special Collections
Hilda Kuper papers
circa 1930-1992
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kuper, Hilda
LSC.1343
35.0 Linear Feet (70 boxes and 8 oversize boxes)
Hilda Kuper (1911- ) was a professor of Anthropology at UCLA (1963-78) specializing in South Africa, Swaziland, and the Swazi. The collection consists of Dr. Kuper's correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, photographs, research, and teaching materials.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Professor Hilda Kuper, 1982, 1987, 1988.
Gift of Mary and Jenny Kuper, 1994.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942332703606533
Biography
Hilda Kuper was born in Rhodesia (Zimbabwe), 1911; married Leo Kuper (1935); BA (1935) and MA (1934), University of Witwatersrand; Ph.D, London School of Economics (1942); Professor of Anthropology, UCLA (1963-78) as well as lecturer at various universities; recipient of numerous awards and fellowships; author of several books and articles, she is best known for her work on South Africa, Swaziland, and the Swazi.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, notes, notebooks, photographs, research, and teaching materials related to anthropologist Dr. Hilda Kuper. Includes her work on the peoples and cultures in South Africa, including Natal and Swaziland.
Swaziland.; Manuscripts for publication; Swazi (African people).; Anthropologists -- Archives.; Correspondence.; Kuper, Hilda--Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles. Department. of Anthropology--Faculty -- Archives
- Indians. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
- India--articles and research materials. (Box 5)
- Notes and original data., 1953-1954. (Box 6)
- India materials. (Box 7)
- Reports, conference proceedings, M.A. on Indians., 1954-1958. (Box 8)
- Notes, original data, including surveys, manuscripts of writings. (Box 9)
- Indians in South Africa, notes and research materials. (Box 10)
- Indians in South Africa, notes and research materials. (Box 11, Box 12)
- Geography and history. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Research notes. Including Freetown ..., True Negro, West Africa. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- S. & E.--Territorial Organization--Africa. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Kinship. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Anthro 139--Peoples of S.E. Africa. (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Research notes--Econ. (Box 13, Folder 6)
- 128 Kinship. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Kinship--research notes. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Kinship lecture notes. (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Kinship and marriage. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Kinship--research notes. (Box 13, Folder 11)
- India notebooks (F. Meer notebooks)., 19 items. (Box 14)
- Indian notebooks, stories (H.K) (incomplete)., 24 items. (Box 15)
- Swaziland--clippings, pamphlets. Jubilee., 1981 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Reprints, papers by Hilda Kuper. (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Papers by Hilda Kuper. (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Sobhuza, King at the crossroads by Dr. Hilda Kuper., Transcript of interview. (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Hilda Kuper, by Gelya Frank., June 28, 1979.; Rough transcript. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  Scope and Contents note
  re Sobhuza II (1978).
- Biography as interpretation. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  With notes re her biography, Sobhuza II.
- The Diviner and the Detective [by] Hilda Kuper. (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Papers on tradition. (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Notes, research material on biography. (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Levi-Strauss - language - myth - religion. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  re witchcraft, animism, birth and death ceremonies, and other topics.
- South African--Indian notebooks., 22 items. (Box 17)
- Indian notes--caste., [2 folders.] (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 3 and 3P. (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 4C. (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 4N. (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 5B. (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 5G. (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 6G. (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 6N. (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 6S. (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 7G. (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 7S. (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 8 and 8G. (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 8M. (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 8R. (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 9. (Box 18, Folder 16)
- Questionnaire responses--Standard 10. (Box 18, Folder 17)
- Notebook-- (Box 19, Folder 1)
  re Indian people in South and East Africa.
- Regina Twala--, Photocopy of manuscript. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  re conversations with Swazi people.
- Proposal--Biography of King Sobhuza II of Swaziland. Submitted by HK to the Ford Foundation., May 1972. (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Swazi law. (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Notes on Swazi language. (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Typescript of manuscript-- (Box 19, Folder 6)
  re Indians in South & East Africa.
- Chart of blood relatives & key--Zulu kinship system (Box 19, Folder 7)
- Caste--notebooks., 4 items. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Social structure & values of Durban Hindu (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Caste--letter to HK from Bryan., August 27, 1965. (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Caste--sketches of decorative tattoo designs. (Box 19, Folder 11)
- Caste--Indians in Fiji by Carole J. Turkenik. Paper for Anthro 256B., 1966. (Box 19, Folder 12)
- Ideology & Content of Caste Among the Indians in East Africa. By HK. (Box 19, Folder 13)
- Racial Conflict in E. Africa with Implications for... Paper by Shri R.R. Ranchandani. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  re people of Indian origin.
- Caste--Some Notes on the Asians in East Africa. Paper by Theodore Ravetz, Sociology 299A., 1966. (Box 19, Folder 15)
- Caste--Leadership in an Asian community by Dr. R.H. Desai. (Box 19, Folder 16)
- Caste--The Asians in East Africa by Shizumi Yokoo. (Box 19, Folder 17)
- Caste--Caste in a Natal Hindu Community. Paper by Birbal Rambiritch and Pierre L. van den Berghe. (Box 19, Folder 18)
- Caste--Race Attitudes in Durban, South Africa. Paper by Pierre L. van den Berghe. (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Caste--African & Indian adaptation to Western ... Paper by Dr. Hilda Kuper. (Box 19, Folder 20)
- Caste--Change in Caste of the South African Indian. By Hilda Kuper. Published in Race Relations Journal, vol.22 no.4, (1955). (Box 19, Folder 21)
- Notebook--NTU, La Pensee Nyambe-Dieu. (Box 20, Folder 1)
- New Age--various issues from Published in Cape Town, South Africa., 1959. (Box 20, Folder 2)
- Caste--Reprint copies of articles by Hilda Kuper. (Box 21, Folder 1)
- Caste--The Indian as a South Africa [by Hilda Kuper]. (Box 21, Folder 2)
- Caste--Questionnaire and responses--Standard 5. ... to obtain background of high school students. (Box 21, Folder 3)
- Manuscript pages re Gandhi. (Box 21, Folder 4)
- Data transcribed from India notebooks., [2 folders.] (Box 21, Folder 5-6)
- Stranger 256B-- (Box 21, Folder 7)
  re Swazi stereotypes & concepts of people.
- Research notes--South Africa. (Box 21, Folder 8)
- Letter, clippings, news releases re Swaziland., 1977-1979. (Box 21, Folder 9)
- Sobhuza jubilee and funeral. (Box 21, Folder 10)
  List of countries represented at Sobhuza jubilee & funeral, clippings re Sobhuza's death.
- Clippings, notes re Swaziland constitution. (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Swaziland--diamond jubilee., [3 folders.] (Box 21, Folder 12-14)
- Genealogy/chronology., 1945-1967. (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Swaziland: a Political Study by A.J. Van Wyck. (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Includes student paper on the article and notes.
- Chapter from Sobhuza II by Hilda Kuper., With clippings. (Box 22, Folder 3)
- The death and burial of King Sobhuza II. (Box 22, Folder 4)
  With clippings and research material.
- Bibliography for Swazi religion by Hilda Kuper. (Box 22, Folder 5)
  With correspondence and a student paper.
- The monarchy, the military. (Box 22, Folder 6)
- The Biography of Sobhuza II--, partial manuscript. (Box 22, Folder 7)
- Anthropology and literature by Hilda Kuper. (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Swazi religion by Hilda Kuper. (Box 22, Folder 9)
- Health. (Box 22, Folder 10)
  re health in Africa, with student papers.
- Strangers--notes. (Box 22, Folder 11)
- Anthro 107A and 108A. (Box 22, Folder 12)
- History seminar. (Box 22, Folder 13)
  re Sobhuza II, with research material, draft of letter.
- H. Kuper--Social Anthropology 161. (Box 22, Folder 14)
- Miscegenation in South Africa by Pierre L. van den Bergne. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  With comments by Hilda Kuper.
- Kuby, David--correspondence., [2 folders.] (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
- Classification, --With notes and clipping. (Box 23, Folder 4)
- Hatt, Doyle--correspondence. (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Radcliffe-Brown--Anthro 220. (Box 23, Folder 6)
- Urbanization--South Africa. (Box 23, Folder 7)
- Prinz, Beth--correspondence. (Box 23, Folder 8)
- H.K.--biographical., [2 folders.] (Box 23, Folder 9-10)
- Christmas cards. (Box 23, Folder 11)
- Swaziland--politics & court cases., [2 folders.] (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- --Swaziland., 1964 (Box 24, Folder 3)
- --Swaziland., 1967 (Box 24, Folder 4)
- --Swaziland., 1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- III Political elite--Swaziland. (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Imbokodvo (political party). (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Sobhuza's proposed trust deed., 1967. (Box 24, Folder 8)
- Correspondence with Swazi. (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Correspondence--Nqaba Dlamini. (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Correspondence--Masitsela Dlamini. (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Swaziland film. (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Kunene. (Box 24, Folder 13)
- Swaziland correspondence--Chris Pappas. (Box 24, Folder 14)
- Nhleko, Musa--correspondence. (Box 24, Folder 15)
- Dlamini, Makhosini correspondence, PM, DPM. (Box 24, Folder 16)
- Matsebula, JSM. (Box 24, Folder 17)
- Sobhuza II--correspondence. (Box 24, Folder 18)
- Swaziland Correspondence--Leo Lovell. (Box 24, Folder 19)
- T. Ghinza--correspondence. (Box 24, Folder 20)
- S.T.M. Sukati--correspondence. (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Swaziland Correspondence--Teachers, C. Giles. (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Swazi--general correspondence. (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Correspondence--Times of Swaziland. (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Bush & Holt. (Box 25, Folder 5)
  General note
  (see also environment)
- H.K.--stereotypes and symbolism. (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Stereotypes and symbolism. (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Anthro 107A, 200A. (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Questionnaire--partial. (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Peoples of Africa--Fall 1967. (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Monarchy & Military - A Study of Change., (rough draft) (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Statement ..., April 1975. (Box 26, Folder 4)
  re liberation struggle in Zimbabwe .... OAU Ministerial Council: Dar-Es-Salaam.
- John Bird Historical Society, vol.1 no.1--proceedings. (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Anthro. 107A., Fall 1971. (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Speech., April 8, 1975. (Box 26, Folder 7)
  re Republic of Zambia by Vernon J. Mgaangwa. Dar Es Salaam.
- Urbanization. (Box 26, Folder 8)
- C. change & urbanization. (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Broad cat research HK. (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Group Areas Act., 1961. (Box 26, Folder 11)
- A note on premarital pregnancy in an urban location. (Box 26, Folder 12)
- The challenge to urban family life today. African Institute of Race Relations., 1959. (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Urban. (Box 26, Folder 14)
- The settlers, Group Areas Act, Sabotage Act. (Box 26, Folder 15)
- Urban Africans. (Box 26, Folder 16)
- Notes re migration, urbanization. (Box 26, Folder 17)
- Health--urbanization II (book). (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Urban. (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Anthro 256B--paper re Levi-Strauss by E. Hatch, E. Ledell. (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Student papers., [2 folders.] (Box 27, Folder 4-5)
- Pan-African Biography colloquium--correspondence., 1982. (Box 27, Folder 6)
- Note card, manuscript pages, syllabus for Anthro 161. (Box 27, Folder 7)
- Manuscripts (Box 27, Folder 8)
  --re Swaziland, colonial period to independence.
- Indians in East Africa. (Box 27, Folder 10)
- clippings re Swaziland., 1981 (Box 27, Folder 11)
- The Structure of the Indian Community in Kampala. By H.S. Morris. (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Urbanization 279-1971. (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Indian material--History., Manuscript, typescript(carbon). (Box 27, Folder 14)
- [clippings re Swaziland., 1983 (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Economics., 1967-68. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Scrapbook of clippings re Swaziland.
- Education (and recreation) Health--welfare--religion. (Box 28, Folder 2)
- Independence., 1968 & 1969. (Box 28, Folder 3)
- Politics--Book 1., 1967-1968. (Box 29, Folder 1)
- January-May, vol.1 Cuttings & letters., 1983. (Box 29, Folder 2)
- , vol.2., June-September 1983 (Box 29, Folder 3)
- , vol.3., August-September 1983 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- April 1981-May 1982. (Box 31, Folder 1)
- June-September 1982. (Box 31, Folder 2)
  Scrapbook of clippings re Swaziland. vol.2.
- October-December 1982. (Box 31, Folder 3)
  Scrapbook of clippings re Swaziland, vol.3.
- Kinship class., With oversize chart. (Box 31, Folder 4)
- Swaziland. Tribute to Sobhuza II by HK, Drum The Times, (November 1982 September 13, 1982). (Box 31, Folder 5)
- Scrapbook of clippings re Swaziland., 1984-1985. (Box 32, Folder 1)
- Scrapbook of clippings re Swaziland., 1986-1987. (Box 32, Folder 2)
- Planned surveys, D. Pilay, (1951). (Box 33, Folder 1)
- India cuttings, (1958-1960). (Box 33, Folder 2)
- Field notes, interviews., ca. 1953. (Box 33, Folder 3)
- Field notes, interviews., ca. 1953-1954. (Box 33, Folder 4)
- Education., 1953-1956. (Box 33, Folder 5)
- Indian centenary articles., 1960. (Box 33, Folder 6)
- Birdgee survey., ca. 1953-1954. (Box 33, Folder 7)
- Desso surveys., ca. 1953-1954. (Box 33, Folder 8)
- Hindu health., ca. 1953.; Manuscript, field notes, interviews. (Box 34, Folder 1)
- Indian's SA, ca 1953.; manuscript, field notes, interviews. (Box 34, Folder 2)
- An essential introduction from accordion binder, manuscript, field notes, interviews, clippings., (folder 1 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 3)
- 2. The Value of Tradition., (folder 2 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 4)
- 3. Schooling; 4. celebrations of maturity., (folder 3 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 5)
- 4. The Brave Struggle for the Land., (folder 4 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 6)
- 7. Why Are We Fighting?, (folder 5 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 7)
- 7. The Nature of the King., (folder 6 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 8)
- Chapter 14., (folder 7 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 9)
- Chapter 11. The Illusion and Reality of Indirect Rule., (folder 8 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 10)
- The War is Over (the Kundla report)., ca. 1972-1973; (folder 9 of 17) (Box 34, Folder 11)
- Chapter 16. Chiefs of Swaziland., (folder 10 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 1)
- ., 1973; (folder 11 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 2)
- Chapter 10., ca. 1972-1973; (folder 12 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 3)
- Transcribed interviews., ca. 1960-1973; (folder 13 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 4)
- Interviews., ca. 1973; (folder 14 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 5)
- Chapter 15., (folder 15 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 6)
- Suggestions for new constitution., ca. 1973; (folder 16 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Royal salary breakdown, clipping., 1968, 1973; (folder 17 of 17) (Box 35, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous letters questions. from accordion binder, manuscript, field notes, interviews, clippings., 1967; (folder 1 of 16) (Box 35, Folder 9)
- Religion--traditional., (folder 2 of 16) (Box 35, Folder 10)
- Religion--Christian., (folder 3 of 16) (Box 35, Folder 11)
- Religion--death., (folder 4 of 16) Empty. (Box 36, Folder 1)
- Religion--divining., (folder 5 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 2)
- Religion--witchcraft and sorcery., (folder 6 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 3)
- Religion--doctors and magic., (folder 7 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 4)
- Religion--medicines., (folder 8 of 16) empty. (Box 36, Folder 5)
- Kinship--clans., (folder 9 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 6)
- Kinship--genealogies., (folder 10 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 7)
- Kinship--relations among kin., (folder 11 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 8)
- Kinship--homesteads., (folder 12 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 9)
- Marriage, sex relations., (folder 13 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 10)
- Pregnancy, birth, infancy., (folder 14 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 11)
- Children and youth traditionally., ca. 1935-1938; (folder 15 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 12)
- Literature, vocal tales; folklore, vocabulary., (folder 16 of 16) (Box 36, Folder 13)
- Unpublished manuscript. (Box 37, Folder 1)
- Sebenta., July 1966. (Box 37, Folder 2)
- Postscript. (Box 37, Folder 3)
- T. Rangek. (Box 37, Folder 4)
- Articles on Swaziland. (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Ilo conference, notes and papers. (Box 37, Folder 6)
- Allen, Carol. Communication patterns in the Southern RDA. (Box 37, Folder 7)
- Indexes for newspaper clippings of Hilda Kuper. (Box 37, Folder 8)
- Notes on cattle marketing survey. (Box 37, Folder 9)
- Some of the duties of an Induana - Ndabazabantu. (Box 37, Folder 10)
- Biography. (Box 37, Folder 11)
- 1968. (Box 37, Folder 12)
- Invitations. (Box 38, Folder 1)
- Genealogy and chronology file. (Box 38, Folder 2)
- re royal constitutional commission. (Box 38, Folder 3)
- Notes important 'kingship'., 1935 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- Courses. (Box 38, Folder 5)
- Newspaper cuttings., 1982 (Box 38, Folder 6)
- Manuscript fragments. (Box 38, Folder 7)
- Chronology. (Box 38, Folder 8)
- Kuper--Manuscripts and publications. (Box 38, Folder 9)
- Witch. (Box 38, Folder 10)
- Papers re Swaziland. (Box 38, Folder 11)
- Index for spelling of names. (Box 39, Folder 1)
- A.C. Jordan stories. (Box 39, Folder 2)
- Review list. (Box 39, Folder 3)
- Scripps. (Box 39, Folder 4)
- Travel. (Box 39, Folder 5)
- Wenner-Gren Foundation. (Box 39, Folder 6)
- Zambia Conference (L. Thompson). (Box 39, Folder 7)
- Boston. (Box 39, Folder 8)
- Graduate and other committees. (Box 39, Folder 9)
- UCLA employment form. (Box 39, Folder 10)
- Correspondence Desmond Reader, Audrey Richado. (Box 39, Folder 11)
- Religion. (Box 39, Folder 12)
- Encyclopaedia Africana. (Box 39, Folder 13)
- Faculty instructions on graduate students and courses. (Box 39, Folder 14)
- Exam. (Box 39, Folder 15)
- Correspondence about urbanization--Wulf. (Box 40, Folder 1)
- Correspondence--Pierre van den Berghe. (Box 40, Folder 2)
- Correspondence--S.N. Varma, Journal of African & Asian Studies. (Box 40, Folder 3)
- Correspondence--A. Vilakazi. (Box 40, Folder 4)
- Library (Nole Booke). Correspondence--Robert Vosper. (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Correspondence--A witch in my heart. (Box 40, Folder 6)
- Correspondence--Witwatersrand University. (Box 40, Folder 7)
- Ethno films. (Box 40, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous. (Box 40, Folder 9)
- Multi-culture Institute. (Box 40, Folder 10)
- New York Academy of Sciences. (Box 40, Folder 11)
- Orientation. (Box 40, Folder 12)
- M.A. Reading List and exams. (Box 40, Folder 13)
- Graduate students--committees. (Box 40, Folder 14)
- Guggenheim. (Box 40, Folder 15)
- Adaptation of law in Africa. (Box 40, Folder 16)
- National Science Foundation, Dr. Lieban. (Box 40, Folder 17)
- Reviews. (Box 40, Folder 18)
- Publication contracts. (Box 40, Folder 19)
- Correspondence--Max Gluckman. (Box 40, Folder 20)
- Fortes--correspondence. (Box 40, Folder 21)
- Correspondence--Raymond Firth. (Box 40, Folder 22)
- Diope. (Box 40, Folder 23)
- Correspondence--Sally Moore. (Box 40, Folder 24)
- Correspondence--Howard Moorepark. (Box 40, Folder 25)
- Beidelman. (Box 40, Folder 26)
- Correspondence. (Box 40, Folder 27)
- Article and letters (c/c) H.K., 1970-1971. (Box 40, Folder 28)
- Adam Kuper. (Box 40, Folder 29)
- S. Africa. (Box 41, Folder 1)
- Ngubane, Jordan. (Box 41, Folder 2)
- Prinz. (Box 41, Folder 3)
- Dawn Chatty. (Box 41, Folder 4)
- Kaby I. (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Unpublished study of Western Native Township, by H.K., 1945 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Harinck. (Box 41, Folder 7)
- G. Strieker. (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Correspondence., [2 folders.] (Box 41, Folder 9-10)
- HK in garden of Los Angeles home with members of Swaziland Olympic team., 1984 (Box 41, Folder 11)
- Race Relations, vol.12 no.1., 1945. (Box 42, Folder 1)
- Special court of Swaziland case., May 20, 1935. (Box 42, Folder 2)
- Religion in Swaziland, published by UBLS, vol.2., August 1975. (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Wage determinations current in South Africa at 30., June 1973. (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Politics in Swaziland., 1960-1968. (Box 42, Folder 5)
  Selection of reports in The Times of Swaziland.
- Chieftainship in Bantu Africa by Lord Harlech. (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Report on the House of Assembly elections, Swaziland., 1966-1967 (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Swaziland annual report of the prisons department for, 1965. (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Report of seminar on national objectives at independence., 1967. (Box 42, Folder 9)
- Second national development plan., 1973-1977. (Box 42, Folder 10)
- Swazi land tenure, A.J.B. Hughes, University of Natal, Durban., 1964. (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Transcripts of taped interviews with various people. (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Press clippings on economics, Swaziland., 1966-1967.; [notebook] (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Press clippings on education., 1967.; [notebook] (Box 43, Folder 4)
- Notebook containing clippings and notes on Swaziland. (Box 43, Folder 5)
- Stories by HK. (Box 44, Folder 1)
- Writings, articles and clippings by Hilda Kuper., ca. 1945-. (Box 44, Folder 2)
- Short stories and articles. (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Poetry by Hilda Kuper., [2 folders.] (Box 44, Folder 4-5)
- A Witch in my Heart--introduction. (Box 44, Folder 6)
- A Witch in my Heart and Other Stories., Photocopy of typescript. (Box 44, Folder 7)
- Photocopy of field notebook. (Box 44, Folder 8)
- Genealogy of Swazi kings. (Box 44, Folder 9)
- Resident Commissioner's court. List of criminal cases, list of reported cases referred to in the notes, & notes on selected criminal cases. (Box 44, Folder 10)
- Swazi - English translations of phrases. (Box 45, Folder 1)
- Writings by HK., [2 folders.] (Box 45, Folder 2-3)
- Swazi stories. (Box 45, Folder 4)
- Photographs--Swazi National Church Complex. (Box 45, Folder 5)
- Photographs--Swazi Independence., 1973. (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Photographs--Unidentified ceremony with Swazi guards. (Box 45, Folder 7)
- Photographs--Family of King Sobhuza. (Box 45, Folder 8)
- Photographs--King Sobhuza with HK at Reed Dance, Lobamba., September 1981. (Box 45, Folder 9)
- Photographs--Airport arrival of African leaders for King Sobhuza's Diamond Jubilee. (Box 45, Folder 10)
- Photographs--At Spa reception. (Box 45, Folder 11)
- Photographs--Foreign dignitaries meeting King Sobhuza at Diamond Jubilee celebrations. (Box 45, Folder 12)
- Photographs--King Sobhuza Diamond Jubilee celebrations at Somhlolo Stadium., September 1981. (Box 45, Folder 13)
- Photographs-- ceremony., 1973 (Box 45, Folder 14)
- Photographs--Gzina Regiment. (Box 45, Folder 15)
- Photographs--Swaziland countryside., 1973. (Box 45, Folder 16)
- Photographs--HK in Swaziland. (Box 45, Folder 17)
- Photographs--Ceremony., undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
- Photographs--State ceremony. (Box 45, Folder 19)
- Photographs--Various. (Box 45, Folder 20)
- Sobhuza's Christmas card. (Box 45, Folder 21)
- Pamphlets. (Box 46, Folder 1)
- Insert to Chapter 11. (Box 46, Folder 2)
- Assorted materials., 1946-1950. (Box 46, Folder 3)
- Field notes: Swazi cases: witchcraft, etc. (Box 46, Folder 4)
- Swazi student essay competition., 1968. (Box 46, Folder 5)
- Seminar on national objectives at independence., March 1967. (Box 46, Folder 6)
- Inserts. (Box 46, Folder 7)
- History: political changes in structure, visual & institutional. (Box 46, Folder 8)
- Religion in Swaziland, U.B.L.S. vol.1. (Box 46, Folder 9)
- References Chapter 9. (Box 46, Folder 10)
- Genealogy. (Box 46, Folder 11)
- References, Chapter 8. (Box 46, Folder 12)
- Chapter 12. (Box 46, Folder 13)
- Undated speeches. (Box 47, Folder 1)
- King's speeches., 1960. (Box 47, Folder 2)
- King's speeches., 1967. (Box 47, Folder 3)